Guide to the Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans papers
1930-2005
YCAL MSS 754
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
110.22
(213 boxes) + 1 roll
The Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans Papers contain photographic prints, slides, negatives, correspondence, notebooks, drafts of writings, objects, and audiovisual material documenting the careers of Carl Mydans, a photojournalist, and Shelley Smith Mydans, a journalist and novelist. The material dates from 1930 to 2005 and provides insight into the Mydans' careers including their work for Life magazine and their book projects. The papers include photographs taken by Mydans while working for the Farm Security Administration, Life magazine, and Black Star photography agency. The Mydans lived and worked abroad for several years and their papers include photographs taken during their various assignments in Asia and elsewhere. Material relating to the Mydans' friends and colleagues, such as Alfred Eisenstaedt, can be found in the papers.
Mydans, Carl, 1907-2004
Mydans, Shelley Smith
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carl Mydans, Shelley Mydans Griffing, and Seth Mydans, 2005, 2015.
December 2015 Acquisition: Purchased from Shelley Mydans and Seth Mydans on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 166 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Shelley Smith Mydans (1915-2002)
Shelley Smith Mydans (1915-2002), American journalist and novelist.
Carl Mydans (1907-2004)
Carl Mydans (1907-2004), American photojournalist.
Scope and Contents
The Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans Papers contain photographic prints, slides, negatives, correspondence, notebooks, drafts of writings, objects, and audiovisual material documenting the careers of Carl Mydans, a photojournalist, and Shelley Smith Mydans, a journalist and novelist. The material dates from 1930 to 2005 and provides insight into various periods of the Mydans' careers, from their work for Life magazine to their book projects.
Carl Mydans' photography is evident in the various prints, slides, and negatives found in the collection. Mydans' extensive research files and notebooks provide a broader context for his photographs. In his notebooks Mydans recorded his research assignments, insights into his subject material, responses to interview questions, and details regarding camera equipment. The papers also include objects relating to Mydans' work as a photojournalist, such as his camera bag and awards from Kodak and TIME.
Shelley Smith Mydans' work as a journalist and novelist can be traced in the various research files, drafts, and other material relating to her publications, which included The Open City (1945), Thomas: A Novel of The Life, Passion, and Miracles of Becket (1965), and The Vermilion Bridge (1980). As the papers illustrate, the Mydans also worked on books together, as seen in the drafts, contracts, and other material pertaining to their book The Violent Peace (1968).
To a lesser degree the papers also shed light on the Mydans' personal and professional relationships, which included other photographers and journalists, such as Alfred Eisenstaedt ("Eisie").
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Photographs, 1930-1992. II. Subject Files, 1942-2000. III. Personal and Professional Papers, 1962-2000. IV. Writings and Other Papers, 1956-2005. V. Audiovisual Material, 1977-1999. VI. November and December 2015 Acquisitions, 1934-2015.
Life (Chicago, Ill.); Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Journalists -- United States -- Archives; Photojournalism; War correspondents -- United States -- Archives; War photography; Women authors; World War, 1939-1945 -- Photography; Asia -- Pictorial works; China -- Description and travel; China -- Pictorial works; Hong Kong (China) -- Pictorial works; India -- Pictorial works; Indonesia -- Pictorial works; Japan -- Description and travel; Japan -- Pictorial works; Korea -- Pictorial works; Malaysia -- Pictorial works; Mexico -- Pictorial works; Philippines -- Pictorial works; Russia -- Pictorial works; Singapore -- Pictorial works; Thailand -- Pictorial works; Tristan da Cunha -- Pictorial works; Turkey -- Pictorial works; United States -- Pictorial works; Vietnam -- Pictorial works; Audiovisual materials; Audiocassettes -- 20th Century; Negatives (photographic) -- 20th Century; Photographs -- 20th Century; Photographic prints -- 20th Century; Slides (photographs) -- 20th Century; Sound recordings -- 20th Century; Journalists -- United States -- 20th Century; Photojournalists -- United States -- 20th Century; War correspondents -- United States -- 20th Century; Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1898-1995; Mydans, Carl, 1907-2004; Mydans, Shelley Smith; Black Star (Picture agency); United States. Farm Security Administration
- Photographs, 1930-1992; Series I; 33.83; (106 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into three subseries: Prints, Slides, and Negatives.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains printed photographs, slides, and negatives of Carl Mydans' photography, dating from 1930 to 1992. The majority of photographs pertain to Mydans' professional work, including photographs taken for the Farm Security Administration, Life, and Black Star. Notebooks providing contextual information about the photographs can be found in the Personal and Professional Papers series.
  - Prints
    - Tristan Da Cunha (Box 1)
    - ACMS (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - MacArthur and Japan (Box 2)
    - Mai family and Germany (Box 3)
    - Mai family Germany (Box 4)
    - Personalities (Box 5)
    - Portraits (Box 6)
    - Traveling show (Box 7)
    - Traveling show (Box 8)
    - Traveling show (Box 9)
    - Traveling show (Box 10)
    - Traveling show (Box 11)
    - Britain (Box 12)
    - Britain (Box 13)
    - Italy, France, miscellaneous Europe (Box 14)
    - China (Box 15)
    - China (Box 16)
    - China (Box 17)
    - China (Box 18)
    - Duplicates and rejects for retrospective (Box 18)
    - Japan (Box 19)
    - Korea (Box 20)
    - Philippines and Vietnam (Box 21)
    - Russia and Russo-Finish War (Box 22)
    - America war years and post WW II (Box 23)
    - Pre-War America (Box 24)
    - Shanghai/Hong Kong (Box 25)
    - Indo China (Box 25)
    - Angkor Wat (Box 25)
    - Color (Box 26)
    - Various (Box 27)
    - Various (Box 28)
    - Contact prints: various stories, various periods (Box 29)
    - Mounted Balkans stone prints (Box 30)
    - Barbara Bush with AmeriCares in Bosnia (prints and contact sheets), 1993 (Box 31)
    - Beijing (print), 1981 March 25 (Box 31)
    - Heinz B. Biesdorf, Cooperative Extension, Cornell University, story for Money, prints, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Bikini Island (contacts), 1946 (Box 31)
    - Reginald K. Brack, Jr. (empty), 1986 December 23 (Box 31)
    - China, Chou Kou Dien: Peking Man, general Peking scenes, PanAmerican Press Group, contacts, 1981 March 19-25 (Box 31)
    - Billy Graham, Russia, prints, correspondence, schedule, clipping from Time, and copy of "Billy Graham in the Soviet Union", 1984 August-September; 3 (Box 31)
    - Ralph Graves (prints), 1988 April 14 (Box 31)
    - Emily Hahn, New York, prints, 1981 September 3 (Box 31)
    - David Halberstam, contacts, 1979 April 18 (Box 31)
    - David Halberstam, contacts and prints, 1979 April 18 (Box 31)
    - Andrew Heiskell, in his new retirement office, Time & Life Building, 1980 October 1-2 (Box 31)
    - Kelly Johnson, Skunk Works, Burbank, California (prints), 1977 December 19 (Box 31)
    - Joe Kastner, Larchmont, prints, 1986 June 8 (Box 31)
    - Daniel Lang, prints and contacts, 1979 June (Box 31)
    - Joseph P. Lash, Martha's Vineyard, contacts, 1982 August 7 (Box 31)
    - Clare Booth Luce, Washington, contacts, 1977 June (Box 31)
    - John D. MacDonald at summer/fall lakeside house, Pisco, New York, contacts and prints, 1979 September 22 (Box 31)
    - Mollie Parnis, prints, 1977 February 22 (Box 31)
    - Donald Regan and Roger Birk, Merrill Lynch, prints and contacts, 1980 July 16 (Box 31)
    - Andy Rooney, CBS, contacts and prints, 1980 May 12 (Box 31)
    - Arthur Ross, Central Park, New York, contacts and prints, 1979 March; 2 (Box 31)
    - Richard Salant, NBC, in his New York Office, prints and contacts, 1979 September 17 (Box 31)
    - Harrison Salisbury, prints, 1985 September 13 (Box 31)
    - Commodore Sullivan, Manila Salvage, prints and copy of article "Sunken-Treasure Hunt", 1945 (Box 31)
    - Edward K. Thompson, at home in Mahopac, N.Y., prints, 1987 February 14 (Box 31)
    - Thomas H. Wyman, President, CBS, contact sheets, 1980 June 12 (Box 31)
    - Xeroxes of photos (Box 32)
    - Xeroxes of photos (Box 33)
    - Xeroxes of photos (Box 34)
    - Xeroxes of photos (Box 35)
  - Slides
    Organized into two groupings: Housed in Slide Boxes and Housed in Sleeves.
    - Housed in Slide Boxes
      - Shenandoah Valley and Warrenton, Virginia on cross-country trip with Shelley, 1939 June (Box 36)
      - Philippines: Pre-war and war, 1939-1940; (7 slide boxes) (Box 36)
      - Honolulu: Alex McDonald and Garry Underhill, 1940 (Box 36)
      - Langchow, China: Shelley and Carl Mydans near Langchow, China, by curious Chinese on bus trip to interior, 1941 (Box 36)
      - Chungking, China, from China-Burma India book (Time-Life books), 1941 (Box 36)
      - MacArthur wading ashore on Luzon, Philippines, five dupes, 1945 (Box 37)
      - Japan
        - Court dance, Amer. Easter Service, 1944 April 16 (Box 37)
        - Kyoto: Rice - Kyoto-Osaka Region, 1946 November (Box 37)
        - Rice, Kyoto Palace, Nara, 1946 (Box 37)
        - Ancient Palace, Kyoto, 1946 November (Box 37)
        - Japan: Rice -- Osaka region, 1946 November (Box 37)
        - Ship Building Chiba Japan, 1946 (Box 37)
        - Promulgation Day, Emperor, 1946 November 3 (Box 37)
        - Emperor reading Imperial Rescript, 1946 November 6 (Box 37)
        - Kyoto -- Japan, 1946 November (Box 37)
        - Kyoto: Margaret Parton; Weldon James, 1946 November 14 (Box 37)
        - "Down with Yoshida" rally Tokyo, Imperial Plaza, 1947 (Box 37)
        - Emperor on Constitution Day, Tokyo, 1947 (Box 37)
        - Emperor's 2nd anniversary, Imperial Plaza, 1949 May 3 (Box 38)
        - Kite flying and Carp (Boy's festival) flying, 1949 June 23 (Box 38)
        - Sea coast, boats, firewood, 1949 September (Box 38)
        - General MacArthur, honor guard, staff, on arrival Walkers body Haneda, 1950 December 24 (Box 38)
        - MacArthur on his 71st birthday, Tokyo, with his honor guard, 1951 January 26 (Box 38)
        - Japan-Lamberts, Imperial Moat, 1951 January-February (Box 38)
        - Air force C-119's and 54's coming in for landing at Ashiya, 1951 February (Box 38)
        - Tokyo: Geisha House party for Time Inc., 1951 March 2 (Box 38)
        - Yoshiwara Parade, undated; (2 slide boxes) (Box 38)
      - Korea
        - Suwon; Joe Fromm and Bill Costall, 1947 (Box 38)
        - Suwon, 1947 May (Box 38)
        - Scenes, 1947 May (Box 38)
        - Korean Farmer's Dance, Seoul: No. 1 - No. 2, 1947 June; (2 slide boxes) (Box 39)
      - Shanghai (weeded), 1948? (Box 39)
      - Angkor Wat - Indochina (weeded), 1950 March 14 (Box 39)
      - Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1951 (Box 39)
      - United Kingdom
        - London Fog, 1952 (Box 39)
        - Fog in London, 1953 (Box 39)
        - Derby, Britain, 1953 (Box 39)
        - Religion / Derby, Britain, 1953 (Box 39)
        - Moby Dick shooting, London, 1954 (Box 39)
        - Lester Bernstein, London, 1954 (Box 39)
        - Salisbury, Britain, 1954 (Box 39)
        - Youghal, Ireland, 1954 July (Box 40)
        - Britain: Herbert Morrison; Clement Attlee; Hugh Gaitskell [empty box], 1955 May (Box 40)
        - Inn of Court Regi. London, 1955 (Box 40)
        - Sir Fitzroy Maclean at Strachur, Argyllshire, on Loch Fyne: No. 1 (weeded), 1964 October (Box 40)
        - Scotland: scenic and general, 1964 October (Box 40)
      - The Big Four - Geneva (weeded), 1955 (Box 40)
        Includes slides of President Dwight D. Eisenhower, Prime Minister Anthony Eden, Premier Nikolai A. Bulganin, and Prime Minister Edgar Faure.
      - Portuguese Bull Fighting, 1955 (Box 40)
      - Cyclotron-Underground, Stockholm, 1955 (Box 40)
      - Nigeria: During Queen Elizabeth's visit: No. 1, 1956 (Box 40)
      - Guatemala, 1958; (2 slide boxes) (Box 41)
      - USSR / Russia
        - USSR-Britain: Russian cruiser visit Britain 1st day, 1956 (Box 41)
        - 43rd Anniversary October Revolution Lenin Stadium, 1959 (Box 41)
        - Winter in Moscow, 1959; (10 slide boxes) (Box 41)
        - American Exposition, Moscow Rejects, 1959 August (Box 41)
        - Khrushchev: his visit to the US, 1959 (Box 41)
        - Sturgeon-caviar, Volga River, USSR, 1960; (7 slide boxes) (Box 41)
        - Russian Easter: Blessing of the Cakes, Village of Medvedova, edge of Moscow, 1960 April 16 (Box 41)
        - Blessings of Cakes Rejects 1 and 2, 1963; (2 slide boxes) (Box 42)
        - Khrushchev: Summit Conference Parks: No. 1 and No. 2, 1960; (2 slide boxes) (Box 42)
        - Yalta, 1960 (Box 42)
        - Trip to Yaroslavl and Zagros, The Diplomatic Dacha, Family, Vadim, Paval, 1960 (Box 42)
        - Scenes from National of Manezh and Red Squares; Moon over Kremlin, 1960 (Box 42)
        - Capt Palm Body being shipped home, 1960 (Box 42)
        - May Day, Red Square, Margaret Truman, Clifton Daniel, 1960 (Box 42)
        - May Day Red Square, day the news spread of the U-2 downing, 1960 (Box 42)
        - Parks scenes, reading etc. With Seth in Moscow outskirts, 1960 (Box 43)
        - Demobilization Soviet Unit No. 60309 (Box 43)
        - Winter sunset Kremlin, 1961 (Box 43)
        - 20 frames of winter in Moscow, taken by Jun Mild for Nikkor Club Magazine, 1982 July (Box 43)
        - Russian Posters (Seth's), undated (Box 43)
        - USSR: Mydans / Lamberts / Marcos, Dacha, undated (Box 43)
      - Washington, D.C., 1959 (Box 43)
      - The Philippines: Bataan, Corregidor, farm scenes, boats, the battle's aftermath (weeded), 1961 (Box 43)
      - Martha's Vineyard
        - Martha's Vineyard: 1961 (Box 43)
        - Martha's Vineyard: 1982, 1982 August; (4 slide boxes) (Box 44)
          Includes slides of Joseph P. Lash.
        - Gold and Yellow Finches, Martha's Vineyard, 1982 August (Box 44)
        - Martha's Vineyard: 1983, 1983 July 24; (3 slide boxes) (Box 44)
          Includes of 25th Anniversary party clam-bake at Martha's Vineyard on Hancock Beach, Ronald and Betsy Dworkin.
        - Martha's Vineyard: 1984, 1984 August; (3 slide boxes) (Box 45)
        - Shelley: Three frames she likes and Martha's Vineyard, 1985 August (Box 45)
        - Martha's Vineyard: 1986, 1986 August; (5 slide boxes) (Box 45)
          Includes slides of breakwater scenes, finches, and Eisie.
        - Martha's Vineyard: 1987, No. 1 - No. 3, (3 slide boxes) (Box 46)
      - Cape Canaveral: general views, mostly home construction, 1962 May (Box 46)
      - Samoa, 1962 July; (2 slide boxes) (Box 46)
      - Paradise Island, Moorea, Tahiti
        Includes negatives and article "An Enchanted Island," Life (1962 December 29).
        - The Wanderer: schooner in Pago Pago and Tahiti, 1962 June (Box 46)
        - Paradise Island: Fish and things, 1962 July; (2 slide boxes) (Box 46)
        - Paradise Island: Fete and Boat Races, 1962 July; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Club Mediterranean, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Plantation, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Moorea: general views, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Jay and Florida Wong, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: The Kellums and the Rutgers, 1962 July; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: The Kelley White Outrigger, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Hugh Kelley, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Kelley Trio, people and establishment, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Moorea: general views, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: General views, 1962 July; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Moorea: its splendor and color, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Native dancers at Hotel Aimeo, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Donald "Muk" McCallum, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: The Burdicks, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Hotel Aimeo and Mrs. Jeanne Winkelstroeter, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Paradise Island: Moorea people, 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Moorea: The Kellums and Rutgers (edited for projection), 1962 July (Box 47)
        - Moorea, undated (Box 47)
        - Tahiti, 1962 July; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
      - Puerto Rico
        - San Juan, 1962 October (Box 47)
        - San Juan, Caribe Hilton, 1962 October (Box 47)
        - Puerto Rico, 1962 November (Box 47)
        - San Juan from Cape Scott; also: ship wrecks, 1964 November (Box 47)
        - The Old Fort and the Cape Scott, 1964 December (Box 47)
        - Beaches, hotels, beaches and waves, 1964 December (Box 47)
      - West Indies
        - Antigua No. 1, 1962 December (Box 47)
        - Antigua, 1963; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
        - Nassau, Bahamas: Beaches and general scenes, 1962 December (Box 47)
        - Nassau, Bahamas: Docks, boats, ships and fish, 1962 December (Box 47)
        - Barbados: West Indies, 1962 December; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
          Includes slides of home of Ronald Tree with Mr. and Mrs. Hamilton Armstrong: Foreign Affairs.
        - West Indies Tourist story: No. 1 and No. 2, 1962 December; (2 slide boxes) (Box 47)
        - Trinidad, 1963 (Box 47)
        - Willemstad, Curacao, 1963 (Box 47)
        - West Indies ??, 1963 (Box 47)
      - Mayan ruins: No. 1 and No. 2, 1962 December 25; (2 slide boxes) (Box 48)
      - Yucatan: Progresso; also: Boats, 1962 December (Box 48)
      - Imperial Dam, Colorado River, near Yuma, Arizona, 1963 January (Box 48)
      - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1963 March (Box 48)
      - Tristan da Cunha
        - Activities (weeded): No. 18, 1963 April (Box 48)
        - Building harbor (first day) (weeded): No. 11, 1963 April (Box 48)
        - Building the Beach Road: No. 6, 1963 April (Box 48)
        - Church (weeded), 1963 April (Box 48)
        - Dance (weeded): No. 7, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - D-Day and unloading and carting: No. 15, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - D-Day and unloading and carting: No. 15 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - D-day and unloading and carting: No. 15 BBBBBB, undated (Box 49)
        - Fishing and animals (weeded): No. 14, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - General scenes: No. 12 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - General scenes: No. 12, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Houses: No. 2, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Houses: No. 2 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - Joseph "The Hero" Glass: No. 10, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Oxen: No. 2, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Oxen: No. 8, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - The Patches: No. 17, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - People: No. 4, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - People: No. 4 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - People: No. 4 BBBBB, undated (Box 49)
        - People: No. 4 CCCCC, undated (Box 49)
        - People: No. 7, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - The Sea, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Sea, beaches, and boats etc.: No. 16 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - Sea, beaches, boats: No. 16, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Settlement scenes: No. 10, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Thatching and sodding: no 13, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Volcano, lava flow and settlement: No. 1, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Volcano (weeded): No. 5, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - USS Spiegel Grove: en route to Recife, Brazil from Tristan da Cunha, 1963 May (Box 49)
        - Views of Settlement: No. 3, 1963 April (Box 49)
        - Views of settlement: No. 3 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - Wheels, carts, tents, shoes and administrative people, etc.: No. 9 AAAAA, undated (Box 49)
        - Wheels, carts, tents, shoes and administrative people, etc.: No. 9, 1963 April (Box 49)
      - Costa Rica: Irazu Volcano and the countryside, 1964 February - March; (2 slide boxes) (Box 49)
      - Costa Rica: Ox-carts, 1964 February - March (Box 49)
      - Bimini Island (British) and the Lerner Marine Laboratory, 1964 May (Box 49)
      - Desert Tracks, Tank Tracks, Arizona Desert, General Patton's Tracks, 1964; (8 slide boxes) (Box 49)
      - Yuma, Arizona: Desert parachute jump, 1964 January (Box 49)
      - Alaska maneuvers, 1964 January (Box 49)
      - Alaska from air, 1964 (Box 49)
      - Easter Island Dec 1964 - Feb 1965, Edited by Black Star 1982
        - Aboard "Cape Scott"; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Crossing the Line "Cape Scott" (weeded), 1964 (Box 50)
        - Arrival dawn and sunrise and views of Island from ship (weeded), 1964 November - December (Box 50)
        - Scenic; prime (weeded), undated; (2 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - Scenic; rejects (weeded), undated; (5 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - Encampment: setting up and completed; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Encampment etc; rejects (weeded) (Box 50)
        - Horse Society; prime, duplicates, and rejects (weeded), undated; (3 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - Agriculture: No. 1 (1-3); rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Tattoos: Cape Scott (weeded), 1964 December (Box 50)
        - Captain Anthony Law, "The Cape Scott" painting on Easter Island (weeded), 1964 December (Box 50)
        - Red Lemieux (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Activities: No. 2 (1-3); rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Dr. Armand Boudreault; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Maps (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - The taking of blood; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Dr. Andrade's going away Sao Sao; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Statues and history; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Sheep & cattle; prime (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - The Pasquenses; prime (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - The Pasquenses; rejects (weeded), undated; (2 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - The Pasquenses; duplicates (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - METEI at work; prime (weeded), undated; (3 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - METEI at work; rejects (weeded), undated; (2 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - METEI at work within Campmento; prime (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - METEI people: portraits; prime (weeded), undated; (3 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - METEI people; rejects (weeded), undated; (2 slide boxes) (Box 50)
        - Work Physiology; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 50)
        - Rana Roraka Crater and statues; prime (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Rana Roraka statues and views; duplicates (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - The Revolution; (prime) weeded, undated (Box 51)
        - Carving images; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Statues and history; rejects (weeded), undated; (2 slide boxes) (Box 51)
        - Sequence: recovering plywood which drifted ashore; prime (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Going away scenes; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Street scenes, etc; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Corrento and Sao Sao; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Houses; rejects (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Cleo Montandon; prime (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Galapagos: Santa Cruz Island, 1965 February (Box 51)
        - Galapagos: the marine iguana, 1965 February (Box 51)
        - Census taking & Cocongo survey: duplicates (weeded), undated (Box 51)
        - Getting meat at the slaughter house; prime (weeded), undated (Box 51)